<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>软件使用说明 on optsimauth的博客</title><link>https://optsimauth.github.io/categories/%E8%BD%AF%E4%BB%B6%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E8%AF%B4%E6%98%8E/</link><description>Recent content in 软件使用说明 on optsimauth的博客</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><copyright>Example Person</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:56:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://optsimauth.github.io/categories/%E8%BD%AF%E4%BB%B6%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E8%AF%B4%E6%98%8E/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ToDoList使用方法</title><link>https://optsimauth.github.io/p/todolist%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:56:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://optsimauth.github.io/p/todolist%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="中文版">中文版
&lt;/h1>&lt;h2 id="总体介绍">总体介绍
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>总共有两个页面，一个日历页面，一个四象限页面&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>日历页面：用于记录未来需要完成的的任务，分为周视图和月视图，在这里把任务分成四种：&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>只要在当天完成的，没有指定时间要求的，比如计划 5 月 20 日去旅游&lt;/li>
&lt;li>只有开始时间要求的，没有截止时间要求的，比如下午 1 点去坐火车&lt;/li>
&lt;li>有截至时间要求的，没有开始时间要求，比如下午 1点前交作业&lt;/li>
&lt;li>开始时间和结束时间都有要求的，比如下午 1 点到 5 点去做实习
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/g8tqfATJiGdXx6m.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="ToDoList.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>四象限页面：在这里主要用于做那些时间不确定的任务，比如计划未来某一天去旅游，完成一个学习目标，在这里将任务划分为四个等级：&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>重要且紧急&lt;/li>
&lt;li>重要但不紧急&lt;/li>
&lt;li>不重要且不紧急&lt;/li>
&lt;li>不重要不紧急
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/OQ6rtg1fNyaTmWk.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="日历页面使用方法">日历页面使用方法
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="组成部分">组成部分
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>日历页面主要由四个部分组成&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/HfE8SK2an6GdTbh.png"
loading="lazy"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 部分为为视图切换按钮，点击后可以不同按钮可以在周视图和月视图之间切换&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 部分为日历主题，高亮显示的是今天的日期，画圈的数字代表今天所选中的日期&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 部分是任务展示部分，用于展示所选日期的任务&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 部分为添加按钮，选中日期-&amp;gt;点击添加按钮，即可添加任务&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="添加任务">添加任务
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>点击想添加任务的日期，按右下角的+按钮，即可进入添加任务页面
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/C9QRMUjTGh1WvZD.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>点击 00:00~00:00即可进入时间选择界面，代表当前任务选择时间
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/iJbW8s1LazqUhBt.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>
上面的部分是该任务选择开始时间，下面的部分是选择该任务结束时间，上下滑动来选择时间&lt;/li>
&lt;li>中间的部分是描述任务内容，点击后输入文本即可&lt;/li>
&lt;li>最下面的部分中右边是确认添加任务按钮，左边是取消添加任务按钮&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="任务显示">任务显示
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/97ljR4miSycAqTF.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>绿色代表只需要今天完成即可的任务&lt;/li>
&lt;li>蓝色代表只有开始时间，没有结束时间的任务&lt;/li>
&lt;li>黄色代表既有开始时间，又有结束时间的任务&lt;/li>
&lt;li>红色代表只有结束时间的任务
有几个弧形就代表有几个任务
同时，复选框的颜色也用于说明该任务是说明类型
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/amyWEtjgdb32XKD.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>点击任务（复选框以外的部分）即可进入编辑任务页面，操作方式与编辑任务类似
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/iDGAFkfHWgdEPNn.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="完成任务">完成任务
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>点击复选框即代表完成该任务，完成的任务会在退出 app 后自动删除&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="额外补充">额外补充
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>点击右上角按钮可以切换为周视图，操作方法与月视图一样
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/10/01/GayNZoTRsS5mzJH.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="四象限界面使用方法">四象限界面使用方法
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="组成部分-1">组成部分
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>主要由四个部分组成&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>重要且紧急（左上角）&lt;/li>
&lt;li>重要但不紧急（右上角）&lt;/li>
&lt;li>不重要且不紧急（左下角）&lt;/li>
&lt;li>不重要不紧急（右下角）&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="添加任务-1">添加任务
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>选中的象限会有高亮提示，如图中所示
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/10/01/cMChnT2VKtbiO6Q.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>
选择象限后，点击右下角+按钮，即可添加任务，添加方式与日历页面下的添加类似，不同点是添加的时候不再支持选择时间&lt;/p>
&lt;p>同样的，点击添加的任务即可编辑任务&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="完成任务-1">完成任务
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>点击复选框即可代表完成任务，也会在退出应用后自动删除&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="english-version">English Version
&lt;/h1>&lt;h2 id="overall-introduction">Overall Introduction
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>There are two pages in total, one for the calendar and one for the quadrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Calendar Page: Used to record tasks that need to be completed in the future, divided into weekly and monthly views. Here, tasks are divided into four types:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Tasks that only need to be completed on the day without a specific time requirement, such as planning to travel on May 20th.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tasks that have a start time requirement but no end time requirement, such as taking a train at 1 PM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tasks that have an end time requirement but no start time requirement, such as handing in homework before 1 PM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tasks that have both a start and end time requirement, such as doing an internship from 1 PM to 5 PM. &lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/g8tqfATJiGdXx6m.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="ToDoList.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Quadrant Page: Mainly used for tasks with uncertain times, such as planning to travel on a certain day in the future, completing a learning goal. Here, tasks are divided into four levels:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Important and urgent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Important but not urgent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not important and not urgent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not important and not urgent &lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/OQ6rtg1fNyaTmWk.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="calendar-page-usage">Calendar Page Usage
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="components">Components
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The calendar page is mainly composed of four parts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/HfE8SK2an6GdTbh.png"
loading="lazy"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Part 1 is the view switch button, which allows you to switch between weekly and monthly views.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part 2 is the calendar theme, with the highlighted date being today, and the circled number representing the selected date.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part 3 is the task display area, used to display tasks for the selected date.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part 4 is the add button, select the date -&amp;gt; click the add button to add a task.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="adding-tasks">Adding Tasks
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Click on the date you want to add a task to, and then click the + button in the lower right corner to enter the task addition page. [&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/C9QRMUjTGh1WvZD.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clicking 00:00~00:00 will take you to the time selection interface, representing the time selection for the current task.  &lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/iJbW8s1LazqUhBt.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
> The upper part is the start time selection for the task, and the lower part is the end time selection. Scroll up and down to select the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The middle part is for describing the task content, just click and enter the text.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The bottom part has the confirm add task button on the right and the cancel add task button on the left.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="task-display">Task Display
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/97ljR4miSycAqTF.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Green represents tasks that only need to be completed today.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blue represents tasks that only have a start time and no end time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yellow represents tasks that have both a start and end time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red represents tasks that only have an end time. The number of arcs represents the number of tasks. At the same time, the color of the checkbox is also used to indicate what type of task it is. [&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/amyWEtjgdb32XKD.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Click on the task (outside the checkbox area) to enter the task editing page, with operations similar to adding a task.
&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/09/30/iDGAFkfHWgdEPNn.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="completing-tasks">Completing Tasks
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Clicking the checkbox represents completing the task, and completed tasks will be automatically deleted after exiting the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="additional-information">Additional Information
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Clicking the button in the upper right corner switches to the weekly view, with the same operation method as the monthly view. &lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/10/01/GayNZoTRsS5mzJH.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quadrant-interface-usage">Quadrant Interface Usage
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="components-1">Components
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>It is mainly composed of four parts.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Important and urgent (upper left corner)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Important but not urgent (upper right corner)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not important and not urgent (lower left corner)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not important and not urgent (lower right corner)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="adding-tasks-1">Adding Tasks
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The selected quadrant will be highlighted as shown in the figure. &lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/10/01/cMChnT2VKtbiO6Q.png"
loading="lazy"
alt="image.png"
> After selecting the quadrant, click the + button in the lower right corner to add a task. The addition method is similar to the one on the calendar page, with the difference being that time selection is not supported when adding. The same, click on the added task to edit the task.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="completing-tasks-1">Completing Tasks
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Clicking the checkbox represents completing the task, which will also be automatically deleted after exiting the app.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>